Gerardo Gonzalez

Columbus, OH | 920-321-8343 | Gerardo.GonzalezLopez@outlook.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

As a software developer, I strive to develop innovative solutions to complex problems and am unafraid of hard work. Throughout my entire academic journey, I have worked full-time, which has instilled in me a strong willingness to learn and an appreciation for every opportunity I get. Balancing my studies and my job has taught me to manage workloads effectively while improving essential skills such as troubleshooting, creative thinking, and problem-solving.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science.

Southern New Hampshire University • Manchester, NH, USA

12/2021 - 06/2024

Relevant Courses with a GPA: 3.99

Intro to Scripting, Discrete Math, Programming Languages, Software Development Life Cycles, Software Security, UI/UX Design and Development, Software Testing Automation and Quality Assurance, Computational Graphics and Visualization, Client/Server Development, Embedded Systems Architectures. Emerging System Architecture & technologies, Mobile Architecture and programming, Secure coding, Full Stack Development, Full Stack Development 2, Reverse Software Engineering.

Associate's Degree in Electrical Engineering Technologies.

Northeast Wisconsin Technical College • Green Bay, WI, USA

01/2019 - 06/2021

Relevant Courses with a GPA: 3.6

Digital: Logic, Sequential, Registers, DC/AC, Machine Wiring and Safety, Electronics: Diodes, Trans-Basic, Op-Amps-Basic, Linear Electronics, Data Communications, Automation, Robotics, Advanced Interfacing, Electronic Circuit Analysis, Power Electricity, Microcontrollers.

PROJECTS

Full Stack Development 1"Travlr" Web App.

Utilized MongoDB, Angular, Express, and Node.js (MERN stack) to create a dynamic web application for browsing travel
destinations, excursions, and user reviews for the user, with an Angular-based admin panel for user management.

Full-Stack Development: "Angular" Web App.

• Employed Docker, Node.js, and AWS to containerize and deploy a web application, migrating the database to DynamoDB and integrating CORS, CRUD, and Serverless service using Lambda, IAM, API Gateway.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Repair Technician

Tech Data, Columbus, OH

01/2022 - Present

 Collaborate with engineers and technicians to plan repairs, and share troubleshooting insights while mentoring and training new hires achieving 70% of all server inspections and enhancing team productivity.

Field Technician

Spectrum, Columbus, OH

06/2021 - 12/2021

 Utilized communication skills to educate customers about services and troubleshoot infrastructure and public utility wiring, ensuring efficient service delivery and achieving a 90%+ customer approval rating.

Certificates

JPMorgan Chase & Co. Software Engineering Lite virtual experience program on Forage

July 2023

Completed an engineering ticket simulation for the credit card rewards department, creating a new class to operationalize an
existing system and writing a comprehensive test suite for validation.

J.P. Morgan Software Engineering Virtual Experience on Forage

June 2023

 Set up a local development environment, fixed repository issues for correct web application output, and used JPMorgan Chase's Perspective library to create a live data feed graph for trader monitoring.

JPMorgan Chase & Co. Agile Job Simulation on Forage

July 2023

 Drafted and prioritized eight user stories using Trello, led daily standups, and conducted sprint reviews and retrospectives to gather feedback and identify improvement opportunities.